A Finding Aid to the Organization of Independent Artists Records, circa 1970s-circa 2003, in the Archives of American Art AAA.orgainda
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition and Installation Files, circa 1970s-circa 2003; Series 3; 13 Linear feet Boxes 5-18
  - Thresholds Reflections Transformations (1996), circa 1996 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Beyond the Surface (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Image in Abstraction (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Installing Nature (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Loosen Up and Enjoy Art Again! (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Mass Mediums (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
  - Of the Body (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Painted Black: An Exhibition of Paintings (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Reflections of Experience (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Sister Dreams (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Thin Thread (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Urban Landscape (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - When Worlds Collide (1997), circa 1997 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Amazons and Avatars (1998) (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Animal Magic (1998), 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - City Light (1998) (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - The Critics' Choice: Ten from the Salon Show (1998), circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Digital Visions: The Creative Edge (1998), circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Drawing the Line (1998) (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Fighting Weight (1998) (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Layered (1998) (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Media Madness (1998), circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Medicinal Madness (1998), circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Self (1998) (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - A Show of Vessels (1998), circa 1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Subtle Jolts (1998), circa 1998 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Views of Summer (1998) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Wall-to-Wall (1998), circa 1998 (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - @ Maya Art Exhibition (1999), circa 1999 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
  - Abstract By Nature (1999) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Balancing Acts (1999) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Barroquism (1999) (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - The Big Apple (1999) (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - City Portraits (1999) (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Conventional Still Lifes (1999), 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Food for Thought (1999), 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Four Reflections of Our Expanding Universe (1999) (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - From Union Square to Battery Park: 5 Painters (1999) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Gotham Living (1999), circa 1999 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - A Millenium of Memory (1999) (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Nesting (1999) (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Nude/ Naked (1999) (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Photographic Memories (1999) (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Places in Time (1999) (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Pregnant Sculpture (1999) (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Reconstructed Human Surfaces (1999) (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Refrigerator Magnet Show (1999) (Box 15, Folder 25-27)
  - Seascapes (1999) (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Sense of Place (1999) (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Storytellers (1999) (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Thinking Digitally (1999), circa 1999 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Touching Time (1999) (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Wild Things (1999) (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - IV - Interior Visions (2000) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 2nd Refrigerator Magnet Show (2000) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Beyond Bricks and Mortar (2000) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The Cat Show (2000) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Critics' Choice (2000), 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - Elements 2000 (2000) (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - Exotic Embellishments (2000) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The Fertile Mind (2000) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Fireworks - artistBooks (2000) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Mapping Spaces (2000) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Mosaic (2000) (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Needs - Unmet (2000) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Patterned Behavior (2000) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Petrogenesis: The Origin of Rocks (2000) (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Similar by Content (2000) (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Sleeping on the Beach: Four Artists from Miami (2000) (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Undercurrent (2000) (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Y2K-aotic: Uncensored All-Media Salon Show (2000) (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
  - Automatic Drawings (2001) (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Aylene Fallah Exhibition (2001) (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - The Critics' Choice - From Small Works Salon Show (2001) (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Different Voices (2001) (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Elise Engler: Everybody Gets One (2001) (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - The Insomnia Show (2001) (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - John Carey Exhibition (2001) (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Life Links (2001) (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Mary Ting: Month of Poison (2001), 1 Floppy discs (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Matthew Tischler: Photographic Works (2001) (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - A Painter's Legacy - James Gahagan (2001) (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Paperworks (2001) (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Perspective (2001) (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Rest (2001) (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Shadows (David Wojnarowicz): Paintings by F. Douglas Blanchard (2001) (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Small Works Salon Show (2001) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Small Worlds (2001) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The State of Things (2001) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Susan Hensel: Assembling Memory (2001), 2000-2001; 1 Floppy discs (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Uncommon Portrayals (2001) (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
  - Weaving Bridges I (2001) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Weaving Bridges II (2001), 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - America: Photographs by Jeremi Bialows (2002) (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Bon a' tirer: Five Years at Grand Press (2002) (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Complexity of Simplicity (2002) (Box 17, Folder 12-13)
  - In the Presence of Family: Photographic Portraits of Brooklyn Families by Ann Rosen (2002) (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Matthew Deleget - Archetypes (2002) (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - OIA National Juried Exhibition (2002) (Box 17, Folder 16-18)
  - Portraits of Places (2002) (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Recent Multiple Projects x 5 (2002) (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Recent Works on Paper (2002) (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Selections (2002) (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Silk Drawings - Akiko Kotani (2002) (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Susan Palmisano - Eating Lessons: Recent Paitings (2002) (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Transmigrations by Viktor Koen (2002) (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Using Double Vision: 7 Representational Painters (2002) (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - William Crow - Discursive Spaces (2002) (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Brave New World (2003) (Box 17, Folder 28-29)
  - Continuums (2003) (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Deluxe (2003) (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Faulty Diction: New York by Catherine Gass (2003) (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Life Forms and Geometry (2003) (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Photography: In Black and White (2003), 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Point of Origin (2003) (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Shells - Sculpture by Ping-Yu, Pan (2003) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Various Exhibitions, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
  - Various Exhibitions, circa 1980s-circa 1990s (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
  - Various Exhibitions, circa 1984-circa 1985 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Various Exhibitions, circa 1991 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Various Exhibitions, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
  - Various Exhibitions, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Artists' Files, circa 1980-circa 1990s; Series 4; 0.2 Linear feet Box 18
  Artists' files contain various resume materials, slides, and photographs about artists, including Hera, Tom Klem, Mary Shaffer (includes one videocassette), and a few others.
  - Hera, circa 1992 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Klem, Tom, circa 1980-1996 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Shaffer, Mary, circa 1990s; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) "A Natural Force" (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Various Artists, circa 1990s (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
- Financial and Legal Records, circa 1970s-2002; Series 5; 6.9 Linear feet Box 18-25, 29
  Found here are award letters for grants received; grant applications and information; budget materials; check stubs; consultant agreements; deposit books; an event ledger for "Rubin's Roast"; nine exhibition and operations ledgers; fundraising information and funding materials; invoices, bills, and receipts; liability and program insurance materials; receipt books; tax materials and exemptions; Warren Tanner Memorial Fund savings accounts; and legal materials concerning the Richard Serra sculpture debate and the position of the executive director.
  - Audit, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Award Letters, Grants Received, circa 1984-circa 1995 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Bank Statements, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Budget Information, 1979-circa 1990s (Box 18, Folder 20-25)
  - Charities Registration, New York State, 1979-1986 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Checks, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Check Stubs, circa 1991-1993 (Box 18, Folder 28-29)
  - Consultants, Fee Agreements, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Corporate Resolutions Certificate, circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Deposit Books, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Deposit Books, 1986-1990 (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
  - Deposits, 1981-1995 (Box 19, Folder 5-23)
  - Event Ledger, "Rubin's Roast", 1984 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Financial Reports, 1978-1984 (Box 19, Folder 25-28)
  - Financial Reports, circa 1985-1997; 4 Floppy discs (Box 20, Folder 1-24)
  - Funding, circa 1970s-circa 1985 (Box 20, Folder 25-28)
  - General Financial Material, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 29-33)
  - General Services Administration, circa 1988 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Grant Materials, circa 1985-1993 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Grant Materials, 1987-1995 (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Grants, Art Matters, Inc., circa 1986 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Grants, DCA, 1978-1998 (Box 21, Folder 5-12)
  - Grants, Exxon Corporation, circa 1985-1988 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Grants, Marine Midlands Bank, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Grants, Mobile Oil Corporation, 1978-1988 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Grants, Mobile Foundation, Inc., circa 1980s (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Grants, NEA, circa 1980-1997 (Box 21, Folder 17-22)
  - Grants, NYFA, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Grants, NYSCA, circa 1977-circa 1996 (Box 21, Folder 24-37)
  - Grants, NY Common Grant, circa 1994-circa 1995 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Grants, Puffin Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Grants, Rockefeller Brothers, circa 1978 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Grants, SICA, 1984-1987 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Invoices, Bills, and Receipts, 1980-1990 (Box 22, Folder 1-29)
  - Invoices, Bills, and Receipts, circa 1988-1996 (Box 23, Folder 1-26)
  - Invoices, Bills, and Receipts, 1994-1996 (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
  - Law and Position of Executive Director, 1992-1993 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Ledgers, circa 1980s-1996 (Box 24, Folder 7-15)
    Oversized material housed in Box 29, Folder 1.
  - Legal Materials, 1978-1997 (Box 24, Folder 16-17)
  - Liability Insurance, circa 1994-1996 (Box 24, Folder 18-20)
  - OIA Corporation, circa 1977-1990 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Program Insurance, circa 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 22-23)
  - Receipt Books, circa 1991-1993 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Reimbursements, 1981-1984 (Box 24, Folder 25-27)
  - Richard Serra Sculpture Debate, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 28-29)
  - Staten Island Fundraising, circa 1990 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Tax Exemption, circa 1986 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Tax Materials, circa 1993 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Tax Materials, 1994-1998 (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
  - Warren Tanner Memorial Fund Savings, 1991-1994 (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
  - Oversized Ledgers, from Box 24, Folder 11, 1988-1991 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Printed Material, circa 1970s-circa 2002; Series 6; 3.1 Linear feet Boxes 25-29, OV30
  Printed materials include newspaper and magazine clippings, press releases, flyers, OIA newsletters, and reviews. Also included are exhibition announcements and postcards, exhibition catalogs, and posters.
  - Artspeak Newspaper, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, circa 1977-2002 (Box 25, Folder 9-20)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Press Releases, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 21-25)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Press Releases, circa 1990s-2002 (Box 26, Folder 1-15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1977-1991 (Box 26, Folder 16-24)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1990s-1994 (Box 27, Folder 1-8)
  - Exhibition Posters, 1978-1988 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 29, Folder 2, and OV30.
  - Flyers of Clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Gallery Guides, circa 2002 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - General Exhibition Materials, 1977-circa 1990s (Box 27, Folder 12-18)
  - General Printed Material, circa 1976-1985 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Magazines, 1986-circa 1994 (Box 27, Folder 20-21)
  - Newsletters, 1977-1994 (Box 27, Folder 22-24)
  - Newsletters, 1995-2003 (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
  - Press Releases, 1977-1989 (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
  - Publicity and Reviews, circa 1970s-1993 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
  - Oversized Exhibition Posters, from Box 27, Folder 9, 1978-1988 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Exhibition Posters, from Box 27, Folder 9, 1978-1988 (Box 30)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1977-2000; Series 7; 0.7 Linear feet Box 28
  Scrapbook titles were devised for clarity.
  Seven dismantled clippings and exhibition scrapbooks contain exhibition materials, slides and photographs, clippings, price lists, and artists' lists, among other materials.
  - Clippings Scrapbook, circa 1977-circa 1990 (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
  - Exhibition Scrapbook 1, circa 1977-circa 1985 (Box 28, Folder 11-12)
  - Exhibition Scrapbook 2, circa 1977-1992 (Box 28, Folder 13-15)
  - Exhibition Scrapbook 3, 1977-1979 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Scrapbook 4, circa 1978-1999 (Box 28, Folder 17-20)
  - Exhibition Scrapbook 5, 1980-1987 (Box 28, Folder 21-24)
  - Exhibition Scrapbook, Critic's Choice, 2000 (Box 28, Folder 25)
- Photographs, circa 1980s-circa 1990s; Series 8; 0.2 Linear feet Box 28-29
  Photographs depict artwork, exhibitions, and installations. Additional exhibition photographs are found in the exhibition files.
  - Artwork, circa 1980s-circa 1990s (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Exhibitions, circa 1980-circa 1991 (Box 28, Folder 27-29)
    Oversized material housed in Box 29, Folder 3.
  - Oversized Exhibition Photographs, from Box 28, Folder 29, circa 1981 (Box 29, Folder 3)